>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 要更确切地了解这一点，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: To understand
this a little bit more concretely,
我想穿过一个代码在几秒钟的时间里
I wanna walk through a piece of code
which within a few seconds of glancing at
你可以在你的脑海里处决他说我知道这个计划会怎么做
you can in your mind have executed and
said I know what this program is gonna do.
但事实证明这个代码比我们的复杂得多
But it turns out there's a lot more
complexity to this code than we
通常用于处理。
are typically used to dealing with.
我想在接下来的几分钟里训练你思考这个代码
And I'm gonna try to train you over the
next few minutes to think about this code
以更接近 JavaScript 引擎思考方式的方式。
in a way that more closely matches the way
the JavaScript engine thinks about it.
所以我们要用什么声音听起来像个傻
So we're gonna do that by way of what's
gonna sound like a bit of a silly
练习。
exercise.
但但愿它能减轻你的参与和兴趣
But hopefully it'll be lighthearted enough
to keep you engaged and interested.
我们要假装一个对话正在发生
We're going to pretend as if
a conversation is happening
在此 JavaScript 程序的处理中。
in this processing of
the JavaScript program.
会有两个演员，两个实体会说话。
There's going to be two actors,
two entities that are going to be talking.
一个是编译器，是处理 JavaScript 程序的东西。
One is the compiler, the thing that's
processing the JavaScript program.
另一个是作用域管理器，作用域管理器是
The other one is the scope manager, and
scope manager is the one that makes
桶，让弹珠，滴弹珠。
buckets, makes marbles,
drops the marbles in.
是编译器说，嘿，我有这个东西，
It's the compiler who says,
hey, I have this thing, and
是范围内的经理说我要做个计划
it's the scope manager who says,
I'm gonna make a plan for
我要为一个水桶做个计划来做一个大理石的计划
that, I'm gonna make a plan for
a bucket and make a plan for a marble.
这将是我们第一次通过这个程序，就是这个汇编步骤。
And that'll be our first pass through
the program, is that compilation step.
等我们准备好了这些计划之后
And then after we've
set up all those plans,
我们就会回来执行代码
then we'll come back and execute the code.
因此，我们希望根据该对话处理此代码。
So we want to process this code
according to that conversation.
你可以跟我走，你可以大声说出来。
And you can follow along with me,
you can literally speak out loud.
它能帮你这就算是老师们的把戏了
It helps you,
it's sort of an old teacher trick,
如果我让你大声说出来它会把它嵌入你的大脑里
if I get you to say this stuff out loud,
it embeds it more in your brain.
所以当我想让你跟我说话时
So as we go along I want you
to speak out loud with me,
虽然听起来有点傻
even though it sounds a little bit silly.
请记住，在我们的处理阶段，在我们的编译阶段，
Remember, in our processing phase,
in our compilation phase,
我们有一个范围的管理者并且有一个编译器
we have a scope manager and
we have a compiler.
因此，我将扮演编译器的角色，与范围的管理者交谈。
So I'll play the part of compiler
talking to a scope manager.
当我遇到的时候，当我看到第 1 行的时候，当我看到线上的时候，
And when I come across, as I see
here on line 1, when I see on line,
变量声明，不管它是 let 还是常量，或
a var declaration,
whether it's a let or a const, or
这一刻就不重要了
a var isn't relevant at this moment.
但我要用 vars 来简单说明
But I'm gonna use vars just for
the simplicity of illustration.
那是正式声明
That's a formal declaration.
换句话说，我们正在制造一个大理石。
In other words, we're creating a marble.
我们要知道什么颜色的大理石
And we gotta know what color
to make that marble, so
我们要把它添加到某种程度上
we gotta have some scope
that we're adding it to.
在这种情况下，显然它是全球性的，好吗 ?
And in this case,
obviously it's the global scope, okay?
为了简单的讨论
And just for
the simplicity of our discussion,
我要用三种原色
I'm gonna use the three primary colors.
我要说外面的全球范围将会是红色的桶
I'm gonna say the outer global scope
is gonna be the red bucket and
只要我们有内斗我们就会有蓝和绿的
then wherever we have inner buckets
we'll have blue and green, okay?
所以我们有一个红色的桶代表这个全球范围和我，
So we have a red bucket that
represents this global scope and I,
当我看到正式声明如我在第 1 行的时候
being the compiler, whenever I see
a formal declaration like I do on line 1,
我要说，嘿，全球范围，嘿，红桶，我有一份正式声明。
I'm gonna say, hey, global scope, hey,
red bucket, I have a formal declaration.
我这里有个大理石你听说过这个叫老师的吗
I have a marble here, have you ever
heard of this thing called teacher?
我在问这个问题，因为如果它已经知道了
And I'm asking this question because if
it already knows about an identifier of
这个名字老师什么都不用做。
the name teacher,
it doesn't need to do anything.
那是不可操作的
That's a no op.
没有重新申报之类的东西
There's no such thing as redeclaration.
挺好的你已经知道这个大理石了
It's just okay, great,
you already know about this marble.
但在这个特殊情况下，这是第一次编译器会
But in this particular case, since it's
the first time that the compiler would
问了一个叫做老师的变量的全局范围，
have asked the global scope
about a variable called teacher,
那么全球范围就会说 nope ，从没听说过
then the global scope's gonna say,
nope, never heard of it.
但我为你创造了一个红色的大理石
But I've created now a red marble for
you and, pop,
现在我们把它扔进了红桶里
now we just dropped it
into the red bucket.
它还没有被创造过，直到他们才真正创造了
It hadn't actually been created,
that they don't get created for real until
但是从概念上来说，我们是从程序中看到的。
execution, but conceptually we're creating
this plan from what we see in the program.
那么是的，全球性的范围说，我们会做一个红色的大理石
So yes, global scope says, sure,
we'll make a red marble and
我们会把它放到红桶里
we'll drop it into the red bucket.
现在我们在做的是寻找这些正式声明。
Now what we're doing is looking for
these formal declarations.
有时他们看起来像是 1 行的 var 老师。
And sometimes they look
like on line 1 var teacher.
有时，它们看起来像第 3 行，函数或其他类型的声明。
Sometimes they look like line 3,
functions or another kind of declaration.
函数制作一个大理石在这个箱子里
Functions make a marble, in this case,
第 3 行的大理石将被称为 " otherClass" 。
the marble on line 3 would
be called otherClass.
这需要添加到某个范围内。
And that needs to get added to some scope.
因此，如果我以编译器第 3 行的形式运行，
So if I ran across, as the compiler,
line 3, a formal declaration for
一个函数，我将与作用域管理器进行相同的对话。
a function, I would have the same
conversation with the scope manager.
我还会在这里说你的作用域管理器
I'd say hey, scope manager,
compiler here again.
我发现了另一个正式声明，在这个箱子里，有一个叫做 otherClass的大理石。
I found another formal declaration, in
this case for a marble called otherClass.
你以前听过那个标识符吗
Have you ever heard of
that identifier before?
在这种情况下我的答案是什么
And in this case,
what's my answer gonna be?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。 >> Kyle Simpson: Nope，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Nope,
从来没听说过但这里又有什么颜色的大理石
never heard of it, but
here's another, what color marble?
>> 扬声器 2: 红色。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 红色的大理石，因为我们还在全球范围内，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Red marble because
we're still in the global scope,
这里是另一个红色的大理石 bootp
so here's another red marble, boop.
现在红桶里有两个红色的弹珠
So now we have two red
marbles in the red bucket.
这需要注意标识 otherClass
That takes care of
the identifier otherClass
以及标识符老师
as well as the identifier teacher.
现在我是一个很聪明的人
Now, I being the compiler am smart enough
to realize, that's a special kind of
因为一个函数会产生作用域，它会产生一个存储区。
thing, because a function makes scopes,
it makes buckets.
那么，范围经理猜测，我们还需要另一个桶。
So, hey, scope manager guess what,
we're gonna need another bucket.
把这个比喻延伸到一点，现在我们正在制造一个水桶，
And to stretch this metaphor a little bit,
now we're creating a bucket inside of
一个水桶，就像一个巨大的桶，里面还有一个小桶，好吗 ?
a bucket, so like a giant barrel and
then a tiny little bucket inside, okay?
我知道这只是个比喻
I know it's stretching
the metaphor a little bit.
但是现在我们有一个巨大的红桶，里面，哎，
But now we had a giant red barrel and
inside of it, hey,
我们需要一个蓝色水桶因为它是一个功能
scope manager we need a blue bucket,
because it's a function.
所以，范围经理说，我们现在有一个蓝色的水桶，
So scope manager says, sure,
now we got a blue bucket, and
现在我们说的是蓝色的水桶，让我们进入那个功能，
now we are talking about the blue bucket,
and let's step into that function and
将其作为自己的作用域进行讨论，因为它的功能会创建作用域。
talk about it as its own scope,
since that's functions creates scopes.
那么我们接下来的正式声明呢 ?
So where's our next
formal declaration then?
好吧第四行对吧
Well, it's on line 4, right?
第 4 行有另一个正式声明，在此情况下，对于一个名为 " 教师" 的变量。
Line 4 has another formal declaration, in
this case for a variable called teacher.
谈话会像以前一样继续下去
So, the conversation is gonna
continue exactly like before,
虽然我们的名字相同但我们会说
even though it's the same name,
same conversation, we're gonna say, hey,
蓝色存储区， hescope 管理器用于此其他类。
blue bucket, hey scope manager for
this other class.
我有一个叫老师的正式声明，听说过吗 ?
I have a formal declaration for
a marble called teacher, ever heard of it?
现在这个问题的答案可能会让你感到惊讶，因为你可能会想，
Now the answer to that question might
surprise you because you might think,
我们在 1 号线上听说了
sure, we heard about it on line 1!
但记住我们现在要和整个不同的桶说话了
But remember we're talking to
an entire different bucket now.
我们在和蓝桶说话而不是红色的桶好吗
We're talking to the blue bucket,
not the red barrel, okay?
我知道这个比喻太薄了好吧
I know this stretches
the metaphor horribly thin, okay.
但我们在和蓝色桶说话
But we're talking to the blue bucket.
所以我们在说，蓝桶，你有一个叫老师的大理石吗 ?
So we're saying hey, blue bucket,
do you have a marble called teacher?
蓝色桶的反应是什么
And what's blue bucket's response?
范围经理要怎么说?
What's the scope manager going to say?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 但这是你的，什么颜色的大理石?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But
here's your, what color marble?
>演讲者 3: 蓝色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Blue marble.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的蓝色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your blue marble.
好了，现在有两个大理石在两个不同颜色的两个桶里，
Okay, so now there are two marbles in two
separate buckets of two different colors,
尽管他们的名字是一样的
even though they have the same name.
跟我来
Follow me?
顺便说下，在同一名称的不同范围有两个变量，
By the way, having two variables at
different scopes of the same name,
有个词叫 " 影子"
that has a term, it's called shadowing.
听起来像是邪恶什么的都没有什么不好的
Sounds like sort of like evil or
whatever, there's nothing bad about it,
阴影是完全可以的。
shadowing is entirely okay.
但有一个影射的影射
But there is an offshoot of shadowing,
就是现在我们创造了一个叫老师的变量，
which is, now that we've created
a variable called teacher,
我们在其他种类的范围内创建了一个叫做 " 老师 " 的蓝色大理石
we've created a blue marble called
teacher in that other class scope.
那么现在我们无法通过词法来引用
Well, now there's no possible way
that we can reference lexically
第 1 行的变量。
the variable from line 1.
我们不能引用红色的大理石因为现在有一个蓝色的大理石
We can't reference the red marble because
now there's a blue marble of the same
因为有阴暗的原因
name, because of the shadowing.
这是完全可以的，但它确实限制了我们从我们可以获得的东西。
It's totally okay, but
it does limit us from what we can access.
因为那些名字最接近的
Because those names,
it would match the nearest one,
在这个箱子里是蓝色的大理石
which in this case would
be the blue marble.
跟我来
Follow me?
因此，我们期待任何其他正式声明。
So, we look for
any other formal declarations.
能在 otherClass 函数中找到更多吗 ?
Do we find any more in
the otherClass function?
我们看到了 console.log 的内容，但我们没有看到更正式的声明。
We see a reference to console.log, but
we see no more formal declarations.
我们已经完成了 otherClass 函数。
So we're finished with
the otherClass function.
现在我们又回到什么颜色范围了 ?
Now we step back out to what color scope?
>> 扬声器 2: 红色。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red.
>> Kyle Simpson: 红色范围，全局作用域。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The red scope,
the global scope.
我们寻找下一个正式的装饰
And we look for
the next formal decoration.
下一个正式的装饰是什么线 ?
What line do we find the next
formal decoration on?
>> 扬声器 2: 8。 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 第 8 行吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: 8.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: How about line 8?
您在此看到的是一个称为请求的标识的正式函数声明。
You see here the formal function
declaration for an identifier called ask.
对话就像以前一样。
The conversation continues
exactly like before.
谈话说，嘿，什么范围?
The conversation says, hey, what scope?
你有什么事吗
Hey?
>> 扬声器 2: 全局。 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 全球范围，嘿，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Global.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Global scope, hey,
红桶我有一份正式声明
red bucket,
I have a formal declaration for
一个叫问的人有没有听说过
an identifier called ask,
ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。 >> Kyle Simpson: Nope，从未听说过。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Nope, never heard of it.
但这是你的吗
But here's your?
>演讲者 3: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red marble.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 红色的大理石，很棒，你很完美
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Red marble,
great, you're following perfectly.
有一个红色的大理石，因为我们在全球范围内。
There's a red marble,
because we are in the global scope.
这就是颜色大理石与红色桶相匹配的情况。
And that's what color marble
matches with the red bucket.
怎么了
Yes?
>> 扬声器 3: 为何跳过控制台日志?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Why did we
skip over console log?
>> Kyle Simpson: 我们不是从编译的角度跳过它的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We didn't skip over
it from the perspective of compilation.
这是个好问题。
That is a good question.
编译器当然会处理第 5 行，并进行一系列的编译。
The compiler would have certainly handled
line 5 and done a bunch of compilation.
它对我们的范围没有任何影响。
It doesn't have any impact on our scopes.
所以我们缩小了编译器理论的焦点以准备我们的标识符和
So we've narrowed our focus of compiler
theory to preparing our identifiers and
我们的范围
our scopes.
做我们的大理石桶分类
Doing our marble bucket sorting thing.
我们正在跳过有趣的细节
So we're just skipping over
the uninteresting details at
这一点，对。
this point, right.
有完整的关于编译器理论的课程
There's whole courses on compiler
theory that would get into all
第 5 行的 nitty gritty ，但由于它不创建或
the nitty gritty of line 5,
but since it doesn't create or
可以访问我们范围内的任何变量，我们不需要担心它。
access any variables within our scopes,
we don't need to worry about it.
有道理吗
Make sense?
好的问题
Okay, good question.
好了我们只做了一个红色的大理石
All right, so
we just made a red marble called ask.
作为一个很好的编译器，我们注意到它有一个功能。
And being a good compiler we notice
that's attached to a function.
看来我们需要另一个桶了
Guess what, scope manager,
we're gonna need another bucket.
这个我们叫绿桶
This one we'll call the green bucket.
所以范围的管理者，你可以为我们做一个绿色的桶。
So scope manager, could you go ahead and
make a green bucket for us.
Scope 经理说肯定，现在我们进入绿桶的范围，
Scope manager says sure, and now we
step into the scope of the green bucket,
标记在这里的功能好吧
the function labeled ask here, okay.
因此，我们在该职能中寻找正式声明。
So we look for
formal declarations in that function.
我们将在何处找到下一次正式声明?
Where do we find the next
formal declaration?
>> 扬声器 2: 第 9 行。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Line 9.
>> Kyle Simpson: 第 9 行，你在第 9 行看到我有一个 var 声明，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Line 9, you see there
on line 9 I have a var declaration,
所以这才是真正的重复对话的方式也是一样的
so that's getting real repetitive, the
conversation goes exactly the same way.
绿色桶，嘿范围问，我有正式的声明
Hey green bucket, hey scope of ask,
I have a formal declaration for
一个叫什么的
an identifier called?
>> 扬声器 2: 问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Question.
>> 扬声器 3: 问题。 >> Kyle Simpson: 问题，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Question.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Question,
听说过他吗
ever heard of him?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 无。 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 但是?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Nope.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But?
> 演讲者 3: 这里是你的绿色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Here's your green marble.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的绿色大理石，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your green marble,
right?
我们把绿色的大理石和酒放在绿色水桶里
So we get a green marble and
boop we drop it in the green bucket.
现在这很关键
Now, this is critical,
因为你会在第 10 行通知我们有一个标识符
because you'll notice on line 10 we
have a reference to an identifier.
这不是在制造弹珠，所以在这个处理步骤中我们不会担心的
This isn't creating marbles, so in this
processing step we're not gonna worry so
关于创造它的问题
much about creating it.
但我们要了解大理石是从哪里来的
But we are going to have to understand
where that marble comes from,
在接下来的步骤中执行代码时的颜色大理石。
what color marble that is,
when we execute the code in the next step.
所以我们必须正确处理这一大理石分类
So it's critical that we do
this marble sorting correctly
当我们第一次处理密码时
as we process the code the first time.
所以我们已经完成了这个要求的功能，对吧 ?
So we're done with the ask function,
right?
没有更正式的声明了
There's no more formal declarations.
然后我们又回到了全球范围。
And then we step back
out to the global scope.
我们是否在全球范围内发现了更正式的声明 ?
Do we find any more formal
declarations in the global scope?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 好吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay?
那么拇指向上，我们现在已经完成了这个处理阶段，
So thumbs up, we are now done
with that processing stage,
此代码的编译器阶段。
with that compiler phase of this code.
我们剩下的就是所有水桶和所有弹珠的计划。
And what we are left with is a plan for
all the buckets and all the marbles.
我们已经计算了所有存在的范围
We've accounted for
all the scopes that exist and
所有这些都适合的地方
where all the identifiers
fit into all of those.
包括第 10 行中对它们的引用，我们知道是什么颜色的大理石。
Including references to them like on line
10, we know what color marble that is.
你和我一起吗
You with me?
我们都知道这些
We know all of that stuff.
我们把所有的计划都准备好了
We've got all that plan all laid out.
那就是作为执行计划的一部分
That is then handed over as
part of the execution plan so
虚拟机 JavaScript 引擎可以运行此代码。
that the virtual machine,
the JavaScript engine, can run this code.
和我一起吗
Everybody with me?
现在重要的是要注意的是当我们执行代码时
Now it's important to note
that when we execute the code,
没有更多的声明可以做任何事
there's no more declarations for anything.
所有的 vars 都没了
All the vars are gone,
本质上，因为我们不需要再申报任何东西了。
essentially, because we don't
need to declare anything anymore.
我们已经知道该怎么办了
We already know what that's gonna do,
因为我们在编译时就知道了
because we figured that
stuff out at compile time.
所以，一个关键的外卖，不要错过这个。
So, one key takeaway, don't miss this.
一个关键的 takeaway 是在词性限定的语言中， JavaScript 是全部的
One key takeaway is that in a lexically
scoped language which JavaScript is all
在我们处理的范围内所有词法范围
of the scopes that we're dealing with,
all of the lexical scopes and
标识，都是在编译时确定的。
identifiers, that's all
determined at compile time.
在运行时未确定。
It's not determined at run time.
它在运行时使用，但在编译时确定。
It is used at run time, but
it is determined at compile time.
重要的是这让发动机有了很大的动力
And why that matters is,
that allows the engine to much
更有效地优化，因为所有事物都是已知的，并且是固定的。
more efficiently optimize, because
everything is known and it's fixed.
运行期间的任何内容都无法确定此大理石不再是红色的，
Nothing during the run time can determine
that this marble is no longer red,
现在是蓝色的
now it's blue.
一旦我们处理好了我们就知道它是什么颜色的
Once we've processed through, we already
know what color marble it is and
我们的讨论结束了
we're done with that discussion.
因此，它允许 JavaScript 引擎在工作上更有效率。
So that allows the JavaScript engine
to be much more efficient at its job.
你应该得到的外卖
The takeaway that you
should have from that is,
我所做的决定是作者时间决定
the decisions that I've made about
scope are author time decisions.
当我写这个函数的时候我把这个变量放在这里
When I write this function and
I put this variable here,
这意味着那个变量永远是那个颜色的大理石
it means that that variable is
always gonna be that color marble.